Methods of Counting Defect Opportunities
Hello, Mike Harry back with you again.
Where we’re continuing our discussion of defect opportunities.
In other words, what must be right or what could go wrong.
Well, you know, those are both from the same coin.
Heads or tails. Right or wrong.
Either way we look at it, it leads to the same inescapable conclusion.
Now, to bring about our discussion here, of defect opportunities.
I want to focus on an industrial and commercial example.
Specifically, we’ll start here, with the solder joint right there.
We’re going to be soldering and we’re concerned about soldering opportunities.
Defect opportunities where soldering is concerned.
Now, to progress this discussion, let's go over and blow it up.
There again, you can kind of see there’s our solder joint.
And we say to ourselves, well, what could go wrong?
Well, in this case. We have several things that could go wrong. Six, to be specific.
It could be missing solder, a joint could miss solder and not having any at all.
It could be insufficient, have pinholes, have voids.
Not be properly wetted to the circuit board.
And the pull strength could be bad. There’s six of them let’s say.
Now, there may be more, may be less, depending upon which
level of inspection that you are applying.
For example, there is what we call weapon’s specification for
government business and there's commercial.
And of course, the government specifications are more stringent than the commercial.
Therefore, there are more defect categories.
Now, the thing we want to really focus on here for a moment, is the idea here.
That a defect opportunity, at the opportunistic level,
what we have is that it’s either good or bad. It either passes or fails.
For example, where the solder joint is concerned, and we’re looking at missing solder.
Either the solder is there or it's not. Either it’s sufficient or it's not.
There are pinholes or there's not. It either meets the pull strength criteria or it doesn't.
Now the same thing would hold true with our commercial example.
Let's take a transaction. Well with any given transaction, we can say, what must go right?
In other words, what could go wrong? And focus on the defect opportunities
from a transactional prospective.
Well, there would be multiple things that could go wrong with a transaction.
And again, at the opportunity level, it would either be good or it will be bad.
Per opportunity, any given opportunity is either good or it's bad.
Now, let's set up a simple example here.
Let's suppose, for the sake of argument, that we have 100 solder joints per circuit board.
And there are six different types of defect categories
associated with each solder joint.
That's a total of 600 defect opportunities per circuit board.
Now, suppose 50 circuit boards are produced. We make 50 of them.
Times 600 defect opportunities per board, means
that out of the 50 circuit boards produced,
we will create a total of 3000 defect opportunities.
Well that's pretty simple and straightforward and easy to understand.
Now, let's suppose that we observe 200 defects across the 50 circuit boards.
In other words, there's 200 solder joints that are defective
across the 50 circuit boards that we make.
So, in this case. Here we’ll bring it up, so we can see it here.
200 defects across the 50 boards.
So, the defects per circuit board is computed as 200 over 50, or 4.
That says, we would be averaging, and the keyword there is averaging,
four defects per circuit board.
Now,
hence, the defects per solder joint,
would be four per 100.
Why? There's 100 solder joints per board.
Now, we continue, we can now say.
Scrolling on down here.
We'll enlarge our screen.
There we go.
So, the defects per solder joint opportunity would be
.04 divided by 6. Remember, there were
.04 defects per solder joint.
Since there are six unique defect categories, independent
defect categories, per solder joint.
Then we would see .04 over 6 or .0067.
Now we can say, because of that,
the probability of producing a solder joint with zero defects
is e to the minus DPU or 99.33%.
That's to say, the probability of zero defects
in a solder joint is 99.33%.
In other words, were 99.33% certain,
that given the current process capability, we can make a solder joint defect free.
It will pass all six defect categories.
Now owing to that, we can compute the Sigma.
So, the Sigma per solder joint is 3.98.
So, about Four Sigma. So, in this case, we can say that if we produce
this circuit board, make 50 of them, observe 200 defects.
Then per defect opportunity, we’re running a capability
of 3.98 Sigma or Four Sigma, about average.
Now, the same exact thing would hold true for the transactional example.
We would have our defect categories and look at the total number of transactions.
So, if we have six defect categories per transaction.
And there are 100 such transactions made,
we would make a total of 600 defect opportunities.
Doesn’t mean they're going to be defective, it just means it's an opportunity for defect.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.